Please close your eyes,
رجاء أغمضوا أعينكم،
and open your hands.
وأفتحوا أيديكم.
Now imagine what you could place in your hands:
الآن تخيلوا ماذا يمكن أن يكون في أيديكم:
an apple, maybe your wallet.
تفاحة، ربما حافظة نقود.
Now open your eyes.
الآن أفتحوا أعينكم.
What about a life?
ماذا لو كانت روح؟
What you see here is a premature baby.
ما ترونه هنا هو طفل ولد قبل أوانه.
He looks like he's resting peacefully, but in fact he's struggling to stay alive
يبدو وكأنه يرقد بسلام، لكنه في الواقع يعاني للبقاء على قيد الحياة
because he can't regulate his own body temperature.
لأنه لا يستطيع تنظيم درجة حرارة جسمه.
This baby is so tiny he doesn't have
هذا الطفل نحيف للغاية بحيث ليس لديه
enough fat on his body to stay warm.
ما يكفي من الدهون للبقاء دافئاً.
Sadly, 20 million babies like this
بكل أسف، 20 مليون طفل مثل هذا
are born every year around the world.
يولودون كل عام، حول العالم.
Four million of these babies die annually.
يموت أربعة ملايين طفل من أؤلئك سنوياً.
But the bigger problem is that the ones who do survive
لكن المشكلة الأكبر هي أن الناجين منهم
grow up with severe, long-term health problems.
ينشأون مع مشاكل صحية طويلة الأمد.
The reason is because in the first month of a baby's life,
السبب هو أن أول شهر في حياة الطفل،
its only job is to grow.
مهمته فقط أن ينمو.
If it's battling hypothermia, its organs can't develop normally,
إذا كانت درجة حرارته تعاني، فان أعضاءه لا يمكنها أن تنمو طبيعياً،
resulting in a range of health problems
ما ينتج سلسلة من المشاكل الصحية
from diabetes, to heart disease,
من السكري، الى أمراض القلب،
to low I.Q.
إلى إنخفاض الذكاء.
Imagine: Many of these problems could be prevented
تخيلوا، العديد من هذه المشاكل يمكن إيقافها
if these babies were just kept warm.
إذا ظلّ أؤلئك الأطفال دافئين.
That is the primary function of an incubator.
وهذه هي الوظيفة الأساسية للحاضنة.
But traditional incubators require electricity
لكن الحاضنات التقليدية تحتاج لكهرباء
and cost up to 20 thousand dollars.
وتكلف ما يصل ل 20 ألف دولار.
So, you're not going to find them in rural areas of developing countries.
لذا، لن نجدهم في المناطق الريفية من الدولة النامية.
As a result, parents resort to local solutions
ونتيجة لذلك، يلجأ الآباء للحلول المحلية
like tying hot water bottles around their babies' bodies,
مثل لفّ أطفالهم بزجاجات ماء دافئة،
or placing them under light bulbs like the ones you see here --
أو وضعهم تحت المصابيح الكهربائية مثل تلك التي ترونها هنا --
methods that are both ineffective and unsafe.
الأساليب التي ليست كفؤة وليس آمنة على حد سواء.
I've seen this firsthand over and over again.
لقد رأيت هذا بنفسي مراراً وتكراراً.
On one of my first trips to India, I met this young woman, Sevitha,
أحدى رحلاتي الى الهند، قابلت هذه المرأة اليافعة، سيفيزا،
who had just given birth to a tiny premature baby, Rani.
التي أنجبت للتو طفلا قبل آوانه، راني.
She took her baby to the nearest village clinic,
لقد أخذت طفلها الى أقرب عيادة في القرية،
and the doctor advised her to take Rani
ونصحها الطبيب هناك بأخذ راني
to a city hospital so she could be placed in an incubator.
لمستشفى المدينة لذا فلم تستطيع وضعه في الحاضنة.
But that hospital was over four hours away,
لكن ذلك المستشفى كان على بُعد 24 ساعة.
and Sevitha didn't have the means to get there,
ولم تستطيع سيفيزا توفير وسيلة للوصول هناك،
so her baby died.
لذا فقد مات طفلها.
Inspired by this story, and dozens of other similar stories like this,
من وحي هذه القصة ، والكثير من القصص المشابهة مثل هذه،
my team and I realized what was needed was a local solution,
أدرك فريقي وأنا أن ما نحتاجه هو حلول محلية،
something that could work without electricity,
شئ ما يستطيع العمل بدون كهرباء،
that was simple enough for a mother or a midwife to use,
بسيط للغاية تستطيع أم أو القابلة إستخدامه،
given that the majority of births still take place in the home.
نظراً لأن غالبية الولادات تحدث في المنازل.
We needed something that was portable,
كنا في حوجة لشئ ما يكون محمولاً،
something that could be sterilized and reused across multiple babies
شئ ما يمكن تعقيمه وإعادة إستخدامه بين العديد من الأطفال،
and something ultra-low-cost,
وشئ ما يكون بكلفة منخفضة جداً،
compared to the 20,000 dollars
مقارنة بمبلغ ال 20 ألف دولار
that an incubator in the U.S. costs.
وهي تكلفة الحاضنة في الولايات المتحدة.
So, this is what we came up with.
إذاً، هذا ما توصلنا إليه.
What you see here looks nothing like an incubator.
ما ترونه هنا لا يبدو بتاتاً مثل الحاضنة.
It looks like a small sleeping bag for a baby.
إنها تبدو مثل حقيبة النوم الصغيرة للطفل.
You can open it up completely. It's waterproof.
يمكنكم فتحها كلياً. وهي مقاومة للماء.
There's no seams inside so you can sterilize it very easily.
لا توجد طبقات داخلها بحيث يمكنك تعقيمها بسهولة قصوى.
But the magic is in this pouch of wax.
لكن سحر هذه الحقيبة يكمن في انها من الشمع.
This is a phase-change material.
إنها تتخلص من المواد القابلة للتغيير.
It's a wax-like substance with a melting point
إنها مادة شبيهة بالشمع مع درجة إنصهار
of human body temperature, 37 degrees Celsius.
شبيهة بدرجة حرارة الجسم، 37 درجة مئوية.
You can melt this simply using hot water
يمكنك صهرها ببساطة بإستخدام الماء الحار
and then when it melts it's able to maintain one constant temperature
ثم عندما تقوم بغليها فانها قادرة على الحفاظ على درجة حرارة ثابتة
for four to six hours at a time,
لأربع الى ست ساعات كل مرة،
after which you simply reheat the pouch.
التي بعدها تعيد غلي الحقيبة ببساطة.
So, you then place it into this little pocket back here,
ثم، تقوم بوضعها في هذا الجيب الصغير هنا في الخلف،
and it creates a warm micro-environment
وتصنع بيئة صغيرة دافئة
for the baby.
من أجل الطفل.
Looks simple, but we've reiterated this dozens of times
تبدو بسيطة، وقد قمنا بهذا الكثير من الأوقات
by going into the field to talk to doctors, moms and clinicians
بالذهاب الى الميدان والحديث مع الأطباء، الأمهات والفنيين،
to ensure that this really meets the needs of the local communities.
للتأكد من أن هذا بالفعل يفي بإحتياجات المجتمع المحلي.
We plan to launch this product in India in 2010,
نحن نخطط لإطلاق هذا المنتج في الهند في عام 2010.
and the target price point will be 25 dollars,
والسعر المستهدف سيكون 25 دولاراً،
less than 0.1 percent of the cost
أقل من 0.1 في المائة من سعر
of a traditional incubator.
الحاضنات التقليدية.
Over the next five years we hope to save the lives
وخلال الخمس سنوات القادمة نأمل أن ننقذ أرواح
of almost a million babies.
ملايين الأطفال تقريباً.
But the longer-term social impact is a reduction in population growth.
لكن التأثير الإجتماعي على المدى الطويل هو إنخفاض في النمو السكاني.
This seems counterintuitive,
يبدو هذا غير بديهي،
but turns out that as infant mortality is reduced,
لكن أتضح أنه كلما قلّت وفيات الأطفال
population sizes also decrease,
فان عدد السكان أيضاً يقل،
because parents don't need to anticipate
لأن الآباء لن يحتاجوا لتوقع
that their babies are going to die.
أن أطفالهم سيموتوا.
We hope that the Embrace infant warmer
نحن نأمل أن مدفئ الأطفال الرُضّع
and other simple innovations like this
والإبتكارات البسيطة الأخرى مثل هذا
represent a new trend for the future of technology:
ستمثل إتجاه جديد لمستقبل تكنلوجيا:
simple, localized, affordable solutions
ذات حلول بسيطة، محلية، ومنخفضة الكلفة
that have the potential to make huge social impact.
التي لديها القابلية لفعل تأثير ضخم إجتماعياً.
In designing this we followed a few basic principles.
خلال تصميم هذا لقد تبعنا القليل من المبادئ الأساسية.
We really tried to understand the end user,
لقد حاولنا حقاً أن نفهم حوجة المستخدم النهائي،
in this case, people like Sevitha.
في هذه الحالة أناس مثل سيفيزا.
We tried to understand the root of the problem
نحن نحاول فهم جذور المشكلة
rather than being biased by what already exists.
عوضاً عن أن نصبح منحازين للشئ الموجود بالفعل.
And then we thought of the most simple solution we could
ثم فكرنا بأكثر الحلول بساطةً نستطيع تنفيذها
to address this problem.
لحل هذه المشكلة.
In doing this, I believe we can truly bring technology to the masses.
بفعل هذا، أعتقد أنه يمكننا حقاً جلب التكنلوجيا الى الجماهير.
And we can save millions of lives through the simple warmth of an Embrace.
ويمكننا إنقاذ ملايين الأرواح، عبر دفئ بسيط لحاضنة.